contemporist.com 2019-12-19

# | CONTEMPORIST

Welcome to our website. If you continue to browse and use this website, you are agreeing to comply with and be bound by the following terms and conditions of use, which together with our privacy policy govern CONTEMPORIST’s relationship with you in relation to this website. If you disagree with any part of these terms and conditions, please do not use our website.

The term ‘CONTEMPORIST’ or ‘us’ or ‘we’ refers to the owner of the website. The term ‘you’ refers to the user or viewer of our website.

The use of this website is subject to the following terms of use: 

  * The content of the pages of this website is for your general information and use only. It is subject to change without notice.
  * This website uses cookies to monitor browsing preferences. If you do allow cookies to be used, the following personal information may be stored by us for use by third parties: IP address, operating system and browser type.
  * Neither we nor any third parties provide any warranty or guarantee as to the accuracy, timeliness, performance, completeness or suitability of the information and materials found or offered on this website for any particular purpose. You acknowledge that such information and materials may contain inaccuracies or errors and we expressly exclude liability for any such inaccuracies or errors to the fullest extent permitted by law.
  * Your use of any information or materials on this website is entirely at your own risk, for which we shall not be liable.
  * This website contains material which is owned by us. This material includes, but is not limited to, the design, layout, look, appearance and graphics.
  * Unauthorised use of this website may give rise to a claim for damages and/or be a criminal offence. 
  * From time to time this website may also include links to other websites. These links are provided for your convenience to provide further information. They do not signify that we endorse the website(s). We have no responsibility for the content of the linked website(s). 

* * *

CONTEMPORIST (“www.contemporist.com”) is governed by the following Privacy Policy.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of the information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

* * *

## What Information Do We Collect And How Is It Used?

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website:** We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. 

**Information We Collect from Others:** We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment.

 **Automatically-Collected Information:** We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked. 

**Cookies:** We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

* * *

## How Your Information May Be Used

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website; or,
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity. 

* * *

## Third-Party Use Of Personal Information

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

 **Google Analytics** – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

 **Google Feedburner** – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. 

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

* * *

## Anonymous Data

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

* * *

## Cookies

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

* * *

## Advertising

**Display Ads**  
We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personally identifiable information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.

**Retargeting Ads**  
From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

**Affiliate Program Participation**  
The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

CONTEMPORIST is a participant in AWIN and Skimlinks, affiliate advertising programs designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising. As part of AWIN and Skimlinks, the Website will post customized links, provided by AWIN and Skimlinks, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

* * *

## Rights Related To Your Personal Information

**Opt-out** – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at dave@contemporist.com to be removed from our mailing list.

**Access** – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to dave@contemporist.com

**Amend** – You may contact us at dave@contemporist.com to amend or update your personal information.

**Forget** – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to dave@contemporist.com

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

* * *

## Sensitive Personal Information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

* * *

## Children’s Information

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at dave@contemporist.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

* * *

## Contact Information

At any time, please contact us at dave@contemporist.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Last updated: 23rd of May, 2018
